The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: If you guys want me to cover anything
教授：如果你们要我讲任何事情
in particular, is there anything you
特别是你有什么事吗
didn't understand in lecture?
听课没听懂吗
In the last section, I covered the recursion trees
在上一节中，我介绍了递归树
because they will be on the Pset,
因为它们将位于Pset上，
and people said they were a bit unclear,
人们说他们不清楚
so we can do that and cover less of the stuff that I have here.
因此我们可以做到这一点，并减少我在这里拥有的内容。
Or if there's anything else, you can tell me what you want.
或者，如果还有其他问题，您可以告诉我您想要什么。
So there I cover recursion trees because someone said, hey,
所以我覆盖了递归树，因为有人说，嘿，
can you go over that again?
你能再遍一遍吗？
Is there any pain points?
有痛点吗？
No?
没有？
OK.
好。
So then I'm going to give you the same choice
所以我要给你同样的选择
that I gave to people last time, and that
我上次给人的东西
is we can go over recursion trees again,
是我们可以再次遍历递归树，
but if I do that, then I won't have time to go over
但是如果我这样做，我将没有时间去做
the code for deleting a node from a binary search tree.
用于从二叉搜索树中删除节点的代码。
So we'll go through the theory and you guys
所以我们将通过理论，你们
will have to go through the code on your own.
将不得不自己检查代码。
But instead, we'll go over recursion trees again
但是相反，我们将再次遍历递归树
and remember how you solve a recurrence using
并记住如何使用来解决复发
recursion trees.
递归树。
The alternative is we don't do that
另一种选择是我们不这样做
and we complete the deletions part.
然后完成删除部分。
AUDIENCE: I feel like covering deletions,
听众：我想涵盖删除内容，
since we didn't do that in lecture, that would probably
因为我们在演讲中没有这样做，所以很可能
be more helpful.
更有帮助。
PROFESSOR: Let's take a vote.
教授：让我们投票。
Who wants to do deletions in painstaking detail?
谁想删除细心的细节？
So deletions and not recursion?
那么删除而不是递归？
Who wants to do recursion trees and not deletion?
谁想要做递归树而不是删除？
AUDIENCE: It's about equal.
听众：差不多。
PROFESSOR: It's equal and nobody cares.
教授：平等，没有人在乎。
I'm really sad.
我真的很伤心。
AUDIENCE: Let's do both in half detail.
听众：让我们同时做两个细节。
PROFESSOR: OK, sure.
教授：好的，当然。
Who remembers merge sort?
谁记得合并排序？
What does merge sort do really quick?
合并排序能真正快速地完成什么？
AUDIENCE: It takes some sort of unsorted array,
听众：它需要某种未排序的数组，
splits it in half, and then continually splits it,
将其分成两半，然后连续将其分开，
and then once it finally gets to the point
然后终于到了要点
where you have arrays of two elements, then it sorts them,
您有两个元素的数组，然后将它们排序，
and then sorts those, and then sorts those.
然后对它们进行排序，然后对它们进行排序。
It's a fun thing.
这是一件有趣的事。
And then it merges [INAUDIBLE].
然后合并[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: That's so much code.
教授：太多的代码。
I don't like to write much code because for every line of code
我不想写太多代码，因为每一行代码
that you write, you might have a bug in it,
你写的，里面可能有一个bug，
so I like to write less code.
所以我想写更少的代码。
So the way I do it is when I get to an array size of one
所以我的方法是将数组大小设为1
element, I know it's already sorted.
元素，我知道它已经排序。
So merge sort.
所以合并排序。
You have an array, it's unsorted.
您有一个数组，它没有排序。
Split it into two halves, call merge sort on each half,
将其分成两半，在每一半上调用合并排序，
assume that magically, they're going to come back sorted,
假设他们会奇迹般地回来，
and then you merge the sorted halves.
然后合并排序的两半。
How much time does merging take?
合并需要多少时间？
OK.
好。
So the recursion for the running time of merge sort?
那么合并排序运行时间的递归？
AUDIENCE: Why does it take n time?
听众：为什么要花n时间？
Just too large?
太大了吗？
AUDIENCE: Isn't it the finger thing where
听众：这不是手指吗
you take each element, and you're like, this one,
你把每个元素都拿来，就像，
is that greater or less than, then you put it in the array.
是大于还是小于，则将其放入数组。
So you get--
所以你得到-
PROFESSOR: Please take my word for it that it's order n.
教授：请相信，这是命令n。
AUDIENCE: I'll explain it and then I'll be confused.
听众：我会解释，然后会感到困惑。
PROFESSOR: OK, so order n.
教授：好的，所以订购n。
What's the recursion?
什么是递归？
Don't give me the solution because then I
不要给我解决方案，因为那样我
can't do the trees anymore, so give me the recursion
不能再做树了，所以递归给我
before it's solved.
在解决之前。
Give me the recurrence formula.
给我递归公式。
So it starts with T of N, right?
所以它以N的T开头，对吗？
AUDIENCE: It starts with N over 2 plus N, I think.
听众：我认为N开头应为2加上N。
PROFESSOR: Perfect.
教授：完美。
So you take the array, you split it into two,
因此，您将阵列分成两部分，
you call merge sort on the two halves of the arrays.
您可以对两个数组的一半进行合并排序。
So you call merge sort twice.
因此，您两次调用合并排序。
That's why you have a 2 here.
这就是为什么您这里有2。
The 2 matters.
这两个很重要。
Without it, you get a different answer.
没有它，您将得到不同的答案。
And when you call it, the arrays that you
当您调用它时，
give it are half the size, and then merge
给它一半大小，然后合并
takes order and time.
需要命令和时间。
Splitting depends on what you're using to store your arrays.
拆分取决于您用于存储阵列的内容。
Can be constant time or it can be order N. So the time
可以是恒定时间，也可以是阶数N。所以时间
won't change because of split.
不会因为分裂而改变。
How do we solve this recurrence?
我们如何解决这种复发？
The recursion tree method says that we're
递归树方法说我们
going to draw a call graph.
要绘制一个调用图。
So we start out with a call to merge
因此，我们从合并请求开始
sort with an array of size N. Then
用大小为N的数组排序。
it's going to call merge sort again,
它会再次调用合并排序，
but after the array is split.
但是在数组拆分之后。
So it's going to call merge sort twice, size is N over 2.
因此，它将调用合并排序两次，大小为N大于2。
This guy gets an array of N over 2, calls merge sort.
这个家伙得到2个N的数组，调用合并排序。
Two arrays, sizes N over 4, N over 4.
两个数组，大小N大于4，N大于4。
This does the same.
这也一样。
So this goes on forever and ever and ever until at some point
因此，这种情况永远持续下去，直到某个时刻
we reach our base case.
我们达到了基本情况。
So we're going to have a bunch of calls
所以我们要打很多电话
here where the array size is?
这里的数组大小在哪里？
What's our base case?
我们的基本情况是什么？
1.
1。
Excellent.
优秀的。
So this is the call graph for merge sort, and let's
这是合并排序的调用图，让我们
put the base case here so we know what we're talking about.
把基本情况放在这里，这样我们就知道我们在说什么。
T of 1 is theta 1.
T的1是theta 1。
Now inside the nodes, we're going
现在在节点内，我们要
to put the cost for each call without counting
不用计算每次通话的费用
the sub-call, so the children here.
子电话，所以孩子在这里。
That's this guy here, except instead of order N,
就是这个人，除了N阶，
I will write CN.
我会写CN。
Remember how sometimes we use CN instead
记住有时我们有时使用CN代替
of the order of notation?
的顺序？
The reason we do that is if I put in the asymptotic notation,
我们这样做的原因是，如果我采用渐近符号，
then we're going to be tempted to sum them up.
那么我们将很想对它们进行总结。
You're allowed to sum terms using asymptotic notation as
您可以使用渐进表示法对项求和
long as there's a finite number of them,
只要数量有限，
but here, it turns out there's an infinite number of them.
但事实证明，这里有无数个。
Also, if you go this way, you can never go wrong.
同样，如果您采用这种方式，则永远不会出错。
You always get the right answer, so that's
您总是会得到正确的答案，因此
why we switch from order N to CN.
为什么我们从N顺序切换到CN。
In order to merge sort an array of size N,
为了合并排序大小为N的数组，
we're going to merge sort two arrays of size N over 2
我们将合并大小为N的两个超过2的数组
and then spend CN time on doing the merge.
然后花费CN时间进行合并。
What are the costs here?
这里的费用是多少？
To sort an array of N over 2, what's
要将N的数组排序为2，是什么
the cost outside the cost to merge?
合并成本之外的成本？
AUDIENCE: C of N over 2.
观众：C之N，超过2。
PROFESSOR: Perfect.
教授：完美。
C times N over 2.
C乘以N乘以2。
How about here?
那呢
AUDIENCE: C times N over 4.
听众：C乘以N乘以4。
PROFESSOR: Perfect.
教授：完美。
CN over 4.
CN超过4。
My nodes are really ugly.
我的节点真的很丑。
I should have drawn them like this from the beginning.
我应该从一开始就这样吸引他们。
CN over 4.
CN超过4。
There you go.
妳去
How about down here?
在这里怎么样？
AUDIENCE: C of N over 2 to the i.
受众：C大于2等于i。
PROFESSOR: You're going on step ahead.
教授：您将继续前进。
We'll do that right next.
接下来，我们将继续进行操作。
AUDIENCE: C of N over log N, right?
听众：C的N超过对数N，对不对？
Because they're log N levels, so--
因为它们是N级日志，所以-
PROFESSOR: Let's not worry about the number of levels.
教授：我们不用担心级别数。
You're ruining my steps.
你毁了我的脚步
I was going to get to that two steps after this.
在那之后，我打算去那两个步骤。
AUDIENCE: Is it just C?
听众：是C吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So array size is 1, right?
数组大小为1，对吗？
So the cost is C. C, C, C, C. OK, you guys got it
所以成本是C. C，C，C，C.好的，你们知道了
if you're thinking of levels already.
如果您已经在考虑水平。
The next thing I want to do is I want
我想做的下一件事是
to figure out how many levels I have in this tree.
弄清楚我在这棵树中有多少个等级。
Why do I care about that?
我为什么要在乎呢？
The answer for T of N is the sum of all these costs in here
N的T的答案是这里所有这些成本的总和
because the cost of merge sorting an array of size N
因为合并对大小为N的数组进行排序的成本
is the merge sort plus the costs for sorting the two arrays.
是合并排序加上对两个数组进行排序的成本。
And the nodes here keep track of all the time spent
并且这里的节点跟踪所有花费的时间
in recursive sub-calls, so if we can add up everything up,
在递归子调用中，因此，如果我们可以将所有内容加起来，
we have the answer to T of N. It turns out the easiest
我们得到N的T的答案。事实证明最简单
way to do that is to sum up the cost at each level
做到这一点的方法是汇总每个级别的成本
because the costs are this guy copied over here.
因为费用是这个人复制到这里的。
For a level, they tend to be the same,
在某种程度上，它们往往是相同的，
so it's reasonably easy to add them up,
因此将它们加起来相当容易，
except in order to be able to add those up,
为了能够加起来，
you have to know how many levels you have.
您必须知道您有多少个级别。
So how do I know how many levels I have?
那么我怎么知道我有多少级呢？
Someone already told me log N. How do I get to that log N?
有人已经告诉我日志N。如何获取该日志N？
So when I get to the bottommost level,
所以当我到达最底层时，
the number has to be 1, the number next to the node,
该数字必须为1，该节点旁边的数字，
because that's my base case.
因为那是我的基本情况。
When I have a one element array, it's sorted, I'm done.
当我有一个单元素数组时，就完成了排序。
I return.
我回来。
So I can say that for each level,
所以我可以说对于每个级别，
the number next to the node is something as a function of L.
节点旁边的数字是L的函数。
Here, I'm going to say that this is
在这里，我要说的是
N over 1, which is N over 2 to the 0 power.
N大于1，即N大于2等于0的幂。
And this is N over 2, so it's N over 2 to the first power.
这是N乘2，因此它是2乘以N等于第一乘方。
This is N over 2 to the second, and so on and so forth.
这是2到2之间的N，依此类推。
It might not be obvious if you only have two levels.
如果只有两个级别，则可能并不明显。
I don't want to draw a lot on the board
我不想在董事会上花很多钱
because I don't have a lot of space and I'd get my nodes
因为我没有很多空间，所以我得到了节点
all messed into each other.
彼此陷入混乱。
If it takes more than two levels to see the pattern, go for it.
如果需要两个以上的级别来查看模式，请继续尝试。
Expand for three levels, four levels, five levels,
展开三个级别，四个级别，五个级别，
whatever it takes to get it right on a Pset or on a test.
在Pset或测试上进行正确处理所需的一切。
So you see the pattern, then you write the formula
因此，您会看到模式，然后编写公式
for the node size at the level.
在级别上的节点大小。
And assuming this pattern holds, we
假设这种模式成立，我们
see that the size of a node at level l, the size
看到在级别l的节点的大小
is 2 N over 2 to the l minus 1.
是2 N比2减去l减去1。
Fair enough?
很公平？
You can say N over 2 to the l, and forget
您可以对L说2个N
that there's a minus 1, and then the asymptotics will save you,
减一，然后渐近会救你，
so it's no big deal, but this is the real number.
所以没什么大不了的，但这是真实的数字。
So that means that at the bottommost level, at level l,
因此，这意味着在最底层的l层，
this size is going to be 1.
这个大小将是1。
N over 2 to the l minus 1 equals 1.
N大于2等于l减1等于1。
So now this is an equation, so I can solve for l.
所以现在这是一个方程式，所以我可以求解l。
I pull this on the right side, N equals 2 to the l minus 1,
我将其拉到右侧，N等于2减去l减去1，
so l minus 1 equals-- anyone?
所以我减去1等于-有人吗？
The inverse of an exponential?
指数的倒数？
AUDIENCE: I wasn't paying attention.
听众：我没注意。
Sorry.
抱歉。
AUDIENCE: Log N.
听众：登录N。
PROFESSOR: The inverse of an exponential is a logarithm.
教授：指数的倒数是对数。
Keep that in mind for solving 6.006 problems.
为解决6.006问题而牢记这一点。
l minus 1 is log N so l is log n plus 1, roughly log n.
l减1是log N，所以l是log n加1，大约是log n。
I could use log n plus 1 and go through the math.
我可以使用log n加1并进行数学运算。
It's a bit more painful and, because we're
有点痛苦，因为我们
using asymptotics, it doesn't really matter.
使用渐近线，这并不重要。
So now we know how many levels we have.
现在我们知道了多少个级别。
Let's see what's the cost at the level.
让我们看看该级别的成本是多少。
So all the calls at a certain level,
因此，所有电话都处于一定水平，
what's the sum of the costs?
费用总和是多少？
For this level, what's the cost?
对于这个级别，要花多少钱？
CN.
CN
And That was the easy question.
这是一个简单的问题。
Just the root, right?
只是根，对不对？
How about this level?
这个水平怎么样？
Because I have two nodes, the cost in each node is CN over 2.
因为我有两个节点，所以每个节点的成本超过2。
How about this level?
这个水平怎么样？
Four levels, each level CN over 4.
四个级别，每个级别CN大于4。
How about the bottom level?
底层如何？
AUDIENCE: CN.
观众：CN。
PROFESSOR: Why is it CN?
教授：为什么是CN？
AUDIENCE: Because there are N arrays of size 1.
听众：因为有N个大小为1的数组。
PROFESSOR: N arrays of size 1.
教授：N个大小为1的数组。
Excellent.
优秀的。
A cute argument I heard once is you start out with N,
我曾经听过一个可爱的论点，就是你从N开始，
you split it into N over 2 and N over 2.
您将其分为2个N和2个N。
Then you split this guy in N over 4, N over 4,
然后，您将此人分成4个N分以上的N个，
so this is like conservation of mass.
所以这就像守恒
If you start with N and here, you don't end up with N total,
如果您以N开头，那么这里的总和不是N，
then you lost some element somewhere on the way.
然后您在途中某处丢失了一些元素。
So CN.
所以CN。
CN, CN, CN, CN.
CN，CN，CN，CN。
I think I see a pattern.
我想我看到了一个模式。
I think it's reasonable to say that for every level, it's CN.
我认为可以合理地说每个级别都是CN。
And if you write the proof, you can prove that
如果您撰写证明，则可以证明
by using math instead of waving hands.
通过使用数学而不是挥手。
So CN times the number of levels, right?
那么CN乘以水平数吧？
The answer for this guy is C of N is CN times l.
这个人的答案是N的C为CN乘以L。
What's l?
我怎么了
AUDIENCE: N log N.
听众：N logN。
PROFESSOR: Roughly.
教授：大概吧。
OK So order of N log N. C becomes
OK，所以N log N. C的阶变为
order of, l is order of log N, N stays the same.
的顺序，l是对数N的顺序，N保持不变。
Any questions?
任何问题？
Are people getting it or did I confuse you even more?
人们知道了吗？还是我使您更加困惑？
AUDIENCE: We got it.
听众：我们明白了。
PROFESSOR: OK, sweet.
教授：好，甜。
Thank you for the encouragement.
谢谢你的鼓励。
So this gets you through problem one of Pset 2.
因此，这可以解决Pset 2的问题之一。
So in this case, the tree is nicely balanced.
因此，在这种情况下，树是很好的平衡。
The cost at each level is the same.
每个级别的成本是相同的。
When [INAUDIBLE] talked about recursion trees in lectures,
当[听不清]在讲座中谈论递归树时，
he showed two more trees, one where
他又展示了两棵树，其中一棵
pretty much all the cost was up here-- the cost of the children
几乎所有的费用都在这里-孩子们的费用
was negligible-- and one tree where all the cost was
可以忽略不计-一棵树，所有的成本
concentrated here, so the cost of all the inner nodes
集中在这里，所以所有内部节点的成本
was negligible and the leaves were doing all the real work.
可以忽略不计，叶子正在完成所有实际工作。
So don't be scared if your costs aren't the same.
因此，如果您的费用不相同，请不要害怕。
Just sum them up and you'll get to the right answer.
只需对它们进行总结，您将获得正确的答案。
Now I'm going to talk about binary search trees,
现在，我将讨论二进制搜索树，
except I will make a five minute general talk about data
除了我将对数据进行五分钟的一般性讨论
structures before I do that.
在我这样做之前的结构。
So we use the term "data structures."
因此，我们使用术语“数据结构”。
I think we covered it well, and I
我认为我们涵盖得很好，而我
want to give you a couple of tips
想给你一些提示
for dealing with them on Pset 1.
在Pset 1上处理它们。
A data structure is a bunch of algorithms
数据结构是一堆算法
that help you store and then retrieve information.
帮助您存储然后检索信息。
You have two types of algorithms.
您有两种算法。
You have queries, and you have updates.
您有查询，也有更新。
You start out with an empty data structure,
您从一个空的数据结构开始，
like an empty binary search tree or an empty list,
就像一个空的二进制搜索树或一个空列表，
and then you throw some data at it.
然后向它扔一些数据。
That's when you update it.
那就是您更新它的时间。
Then you ask it some questions, and that's when you query it.
然后，您要问一些问题，那就是在查询它时。
Then maybe you throw more data at it, so you do more updates,
然后，也许您要投入更多的数据，因此您需要进行更多的更新，
and you ask more questions, so you do more queries.
并且您提出了更多问题，因此您进行了更多查询。
What are the queries and the updates
什么是查询和更新
for the binary search trees that we talked about in lecture?
我们在讲座中讨论过的二叉搜索树？
AUDIENCE: A query would be like, what's
观众：查询就像是什么
your right child, what's your left child?
你的右孩子，你的左孩子是什么？
PROFESSOR: So that's for a node.
教授：那是给一个节点的。
AUDIENCE: What are you looking for?
听众：您在找什么？
PROFESSOR: I'm looking for something
教授：我在找东西
for the entire infrastructure.
整个基础架构。
So for the entire tree, what's a question
所以对于整棵树，有什么问题
that you would ask the tree?
你会问那棵树吗？
PROFESSOR: Max.
教授：最高
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Min.
最小
AUDIENCE: Next larger.
听众：接下来更大。
PROFESSOR: Next larger.
教授：下一个更大。
Are you looking at the nodes?
您在看节点吗？
AUDIENCE: Is there an are you balanced question?
听众：您有一个平衡的问题吗？
PROFESSOR: Well, I would say that the most popular operation
教授：好吧，我想说这是最受欢迎的手术
in a binary search tree is Search, which
在二叉搜索树中是Search，
looks for-- we call it Find in the code
寻找-我们在代码中将其称为Find
because most code implementations call it Find
因为大多数代码实现都称它为Find
nowadays, but binary search tree.
如今，但是二进制搜索树。
What are you going to do in it?
您打算在其中做什么？
You search for a value.
您搜索一个值。
That's why it has the Search in binary search.
这就是为什么它在二进制搜索中具有“搜索”的原因。
So queries are operations where you ask questions to the data
因此查询是您向数据提出问题的操作
structure and it doesn't change.
结构，它不会改变。
How about updates?
更新如何？
What did we learn for updates?
我们从中学到了什么？
AUDIENCE: Insert.
听众：插入。
PROFESSOR: Excellent.
教授：非常好。
So Insert was covered in lecture,
因此，Insert被演讲所涵盖，
and we're doing Delete today.
今天我们要进行删除
So data structures have this property
因此数据结构具有此属性
that's called the representation invariant, RI,
这就是表示不变式RI
or Rep Invariant.
或Rep不变量。
Actually, before I get there, the rep invariant
其实，在到达那里之前，代表不变式
says that the data in the data structures
说数据结构中的数据
is organized in this way, and as long
是这样组织的，而且只要
as it's organized in this way, the data structure functions
由于以这种方式组织，因此数据结构起作用
correctly.
正确地。
Can someone guess for a sorted array
有人可以猜测一个排序的数组
what's the representation invariant?
什么是表示不变式？
AUDIENCE: It can mean sorted.
听众：可以表示已排序。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
A sorted array should be sorted.
排序后的数组应排序。
Sounds like a very good rep invariant.
听起来像一个非常好的rep不变式。
So the elements should be stored an array.
因此，元素应存储为数组。
Every element should be smaller than any element after it.
每个元素都应小于其后的任何元素。
And as long as the rep invariant holds, so as long
只要rep不变量成立，
as elements are stored in the right way in the data
因为元素以正确的方式存储在数据中
structure, the queries will return the right results.
结构，查询将返回正确的结果。
If the rep invariant doesn't hold,
如果rep不变量不成立，
then God knows what's going to happen.
然后上帝知道会发生什么。
What can you do in a storage array
您可以在存储阵列中做什么
as long as the rep invariant holds?
只要代表不变式成立？
Sorted array.
排序数组。
What's the reason why I would have a sorted array?
为什么要排序数组是什么原因？
What can I do that's fast in a sorted array?
我能快速完成排序数组中的操作吗？
AUDIENCE: Min and Max.
听众：最小和最大。
PROFESSOR: I can do that very fast.
教授：我可以很快做到。
That's good.
那很好。
What's the running time?
几点钟了？
AUDIENCE: A constant.
听众：一个常数。
PROFESSOR: Perfect.
教授：完美。
Min you look at the beginning, Max you look at the end.
最小的你看开始，最大的你看结束。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: Binary search.
受众：二进制搜索。
PROFESSOR: Binary search.
教授：二进制搜索。
That's the other reason for that.
那是另一个原因。
So binary search runs in order log
因此二进制搜索按顺序运行
N time, doesn't have to look at most of the array,
N次，不必看大部分阵列，
tells you whether an element is there are not.
告诉您元素是否不存在。
Now, what if the array is unsorted?
现在，如果数组未排序怎么办？
Will the algorithm work?
该算法会起作用吗？
It might say something isn't there
可能说没有东西
when it actually is there.
当它实际存在时。
You can do binary search on a non-sorted array.
您可以对未排序的数组执行二进制搜索。
So if the rep invariant doesn't hold,
因此，如果rep不变量不成立，
your queries might give you a wrong answer.
您的查询可能会给您错误的答案。
How about updates?
更新如何？
How do you search something in a sorted list?
您如何搜索排序列表中的内容？
AUDIENCE: You find where it should go
观众：您找到应该去的地方
and you move everything.
然后您移动所有东西。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So you have to move everything, make room for it,
因此，您必须移动所有东西，为其腾出空间，
and put it there so that the array is still
并放到那里，以便阵列仍然
sorted at the end.
最后排序。
You can't just append things at the end,
您不能只在结尾附加内容，
even though that would be faster and lazier and less code.
即使这样会更快，更懒惰并且代码更少。
When you do an update to a data structure,
当您更新数据结构时，
you have to make sure that the rep invariant still
您必须确保rep不变
holds at the end.
坚持到底。
Sort of a correctness proof for an update algorithm
某种更新算法的正确性证明
says that if the rep invariant holds at the beginning,
说如果rep不变式在​​开始时成立，
the rep invariant is guaranteed to hold at the end.
代表不变式一定会保留在最后。
Why do we care about this rep invariant stuff?
我们为什么要关心这个代表不变的东西？
Suppose you have a problem, say on the next Pset, that
假设您有一个问题，例如在下一个Pset上，
asks you to find the place that's slow in your code
要求您找到代码中速度较慢的地方
and then speed it up.
然后加快速度。
And suppose you recognize the data structure there,
并假设您认识那里的数据结构，
and you say that's inefficient, and you
你说那效率低下，你
want to implement another data structure that
想要实现另一个数据结构
would be more efficient.
会更有效率。
You're going to implement it.
您将实现它。
You might have bugs in an update.
您可能在更新中存在错误。
How do you find the bugs?
您如何找到错误？
Queries give you the wrong answers.
查询给您错误的答案。
You might do queries a long time after you do updates,
更新后可能会查询很长时间，
and you're not going to know which update failed.
而且您不会知道哪个更新失败。
The right way to do this is you implement the method
正确的方法是实现方法
called Check RI-- that's what I call it-- so
叫做Check RI，这就是我所说的
check the representation invariant.
检查表示形式不变。
And that method walks through the entire data structure
该方法遍历整个数据结构
and make sure that the rep invariant holds,
并确保代表不变式成立，
and if it doesn't, it raises an exception
如果没有，则会引发异常
because you know that whatever you try to do from there
因为您知道从那里尝试做什么
is not going to work, so there's no reason to keep going.
无法正常工作，因此没有理由继续前进。
So at the end of every update, you add a call
因此，在每次更新结束时，您都会添加一个通话
to this Check RI method until you're
直到您
sure that your code is correct.
确保您的代码正确。
And after you're done debugging your code,
在调试完代码后，
you remove this method and you submit the code.
您删除此方法，然后提交代码。
Why do I want to remove the method?
为什么要删除该方法？
It might be painfully slow and inefficient, much slower
它可能会很慢，效率很低，要慢得多
than the actual queries and updates.
比实际的查询和更新。
For example, let's take a heap.
例如，让我们堆一堆。
Do people remember heaps from lecture?
人们还记得演讲中的堆吗？
What's the query for a heap?
对堆的查询是什么？
Say you have a max heap.
假设您有一个最大堆。
What's a query?
什么是查询？
AUDIENCE: Where's the max?
听众：最高限额在哪里？
PROFESSOR: OK, cool.
教授：好的，很酷。
So for a max heap, a query would be max.
因此，对于最大堆，查询将是最大。
Running time?
运行时间？
AUDIENCE: Constant.
听众：不变。
PROFESSOR: Perfect.
教授：完美。
Constant.
不变。
What do you do?
你是做什么？
Look at the top?
看顶部？
AUDIENCE: Yeah, exactly.
听众：是的，确实如此。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Sweet.
甜。
So what are the two popular updates in a max heap?
那么最大堆中两个流行的更新是什么？
AUDIENCE: There would be Insert as well.
听众：也会有插入。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Insert.
插入。
And did we teach you general delete?
并且我们教过您一般删除吗？
Usually Extract Max is simpler.
通常，Extract Max更简单。
That's all you need.
这就是您所需要的。
What's the running time for Insert?
插入的运行时间是几点？
Do people remember heaps?
人们还记得堆吗？
AUDIENCE: I think it was per N, but I'm not completely sure.
听众：我认为是每N个，但我不确定。
PROFESSOR: Anyone else?
教授：还有其他人吗？
It's not.
不是。
Life would be bad if it would be N.
如果它是N，生活将会很糟糕。
AUDIENCE: N squared?
听众：N平方？
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
It's better than N, so you guys are doing a binary search
比N好，所以你们在做二进制搜索
over the few running times that I gave you earlier.
在我之前给您的几个运行时间中。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] add to the N,
观众：[听不清]加到N，
and then you compare your neighbor, and then you
然后你比较你的邻居，然后你
[INAUDIBLE].
[听不清]。
AUDIENCE: If it's an array, there isn't--
听众：如果是数组，就不会-
PROFESSOR: So conceptually, a heap looks like this.
教授：所以从概念上讲，堆看起来像这样。
And yeah, it becomes an array eventually,
是的，它最终成为一个数组，
but let's look at it this way.
但是让我们这样看。
It is a full binary tree.
它是完整的二叉树。
Binary tree means that each node has at most two children,
二叉树表示每个节点最多有两个孩子，
and full means that every level except for the last level
满是指除最后一个级别外的每个级别
is completely populated.
已完全填充。
So every internal node has exactly two children,
所以每个内部节点都有两个孩子
and in here, every node except for some nodes
在这里，除某些节点外，每个节点
and then some nodes after it will not have.
然后它之后的某些节点将没有。
Everything to the left is fully populated,
左侧的所有内容均已完全填充，
and then at some point, you stop having children.
然后在某个时候，您不再有孩子。
It turns out that this is easy to store in an array,
事实证明，这很容易存储在数组中，
but I will not go over that.
但是我不会再说了。
Instead, I want to go over inserting.
相反，我想遍历插入。
What's the rep invariant for a heap?
堆的代表不变式是什么？
AUDIENCE: The max in the top, right?
听众：最上面的最大，对吗？
Well, for max heap, and then the two children
好吧，为了最大堆，然后是两个孩子
are less than the next node.
小于下一个节点。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
So the guy here has to be bigger than these guys,
所以这里的人必须比这些人大，
then the guy here has to be bigger than these guys,
那么这里的人必须比这些人大，
and so on and so forth.
等等等等。
And if you use induction, you can
如果您使用归纳法，您可以
prove that if this is bigger than this,
证明如果这个比这个大，
it has to be bigger than these guys, and bigger
它必须比这些家伙更大，更大
than these guys, and bigger than everything, and it's a max.
比这些家伙，比一切都更大，这是最大的。
That's the reason why we have that rep invariant.
这就是我们使该代表不变的原因。
So the way we insert a node is we add it
所以我们插入节点的方法是添加它
at the bottom, the only place where we could add it.
在底部，这是我们可以添加的唯一位置。
And then if this guy is bigger than this guy,
然后如果这个人比这个人大，
the rep invariant is violated, so we swap them
代表不变式被违反，因此我们将其交换
in order to fix that.
为了解决这个问题。
Now the guy is here.
现在那个家伙在这里。
If this is bigger than this, we do another swap.
如果大于此值，我们将进行另一次交换。
So you're going to go from the bottom of the heap potentially
因此，您可能会从堆的底部开始
all the way up to the root.
一直到根
So the running time of insert is order
所以插入的运行时间是命令
of the height of the heap.
堆的高度。
Now, the heap is a full binary tree.
现在，堆是完整的二叉树。
I said "full."
我说“饱”。
I keep saying "full."
我一直说“满”。
The reason I care about full is that the full binary tree
我关心完全的原因是完全的二叉树
is guaranteed to have a height of log N. It's always
保证高度为N。
log N, where N is the number of nodes.
log N，其中N是节点数。
So inserting in a heap takes log N.
因此，在堆中插入需要日志N。
AUDIENCE: I have a question.
听众：我有一个问题。
Didn't they say that because it's in an array,
他们不是这么说是因为它在一个数组中，
then to find it-- oh no, I guess because you can still
然后找到它-哦不，我想是因为您仍然可以
do the swaps.
做交换。
PROFESSOR: You can still do the swaps
教授：您仍然可以进行交换
when you have it serialized in an array.
当您将其序列化为数组时。
You know that given an item's index,
您知道给定项目的索引，
the parent is that index divided by 2.
父级是该索引除以2。
So you add an element at the end of the array,
因此，您在数组的末尾添加了一个元素，
and then you know what the parent is,
然后你知道父母是谁
and then you keep swapping and swapping and swapping
然后你继续交换和交换
towards the [INAUDIBLE].
向[听不清]。
AUDIENCE: You don't ever have to put it in
听众：您永远不必放入
and shift everything over.
并转移一切。
You're only swapping.
您只是交换。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
You only swap.
您只交换。
That's important.
那很重要
Thanks for asking.
感谢您的询问。
That's important.
那很重要
So log N. Extract max, take my word for it,
因此，登录N。提取最大，相信我，
also log N. What's the running time for checking
也记录N。检查的运行时间是多少
the invariant in a heap?
堆中的不变式？
So to make sure that this guy is a heap, if I had numbers here,
因此，请确保这个人是一个堆，如果我在这里有数字，
what would you have to do?
你要怎么办
AUDIENCE: You'd have to look at every node.
听众：您必须查看每个节点。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So running time?
那么运行时间？
AUDIENCE: Theta of N.
观众：N的Theta。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So if I'm going to submit code for a heap
因此，如果我要提交堆代码
where the operations are our order of log N,
这些操作是我们的日志N的顺序，
or order 1, but then each of these calls Check RI,
或订单1，但随后每个调用RI，
that's going to be painfully slow because I'm
这将是痛苦的缓慢，因为我
making the updates be order N instead of log N.
使更新的顺序为N，而不是日志N。
So you're putting Check RI calls in every update.
因此，您将在每次更新中添加Check RI调用。
You debug your code.
您调试代码。
When you make sure it's correct, you remove those,
如果确定正确无误，则将其删除，
and then you submit the Pset.
然后提交Pset。
Make sense?
说得通？
Sweet.
甜。
And we looked a little bit at heaps, which is good.
我们稍微看了看堆，这很好。
Binary search trees.
二进制搜索树。
So a binary tree is a tree where every node
所以二叉树是一棵树，每个节点
has at most two children.
最多有两个孩子。
When we code this up, we represent a node as a Python
当我们编写代码时，我们将节点表示为Python
object, and for a node, we keep track of the left child,
对象，对于一个节点，我们跟踪左孩子，
of the right child, parent, and then this is a hollow tree.
正确的孩子，父母，然后这是一棵空心树。
It's not very useful.
这不是很有用。
This becomes useful when you start putting keys in the nodes
当您开始将密钥放入节点时，这将变得很有用
so that you can find them and do other things with them.
这样您就可以找到它们并与他们一起做其他事情。
So each node has a key.
因此，每个节点都有一个密钥。
Let me draw a binary search tree.
让我画一个二叉搜索树。
Can people see this?
人们可以看到吗？
So this is a binary tree.
所以这是一个二叉树。
Can someone say something a bit more specific about it?
有人可以说些具体一点吗？
AUDIENCE: It's unbalanced.
听众：不平衡。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
It's imbalanced.
它是不平衡的。
So that means that finding things all the way
因此，这意味着始终寻找事物
at the bottom is going to be expensive.
最底层的将是昂贵的。
What else?
还有什么？
So I said it's a binary tree.
所以我说这是一棵二叉树。
Give me something more specific.
给我一些更具体的东西。
So binary tree just means that every node has two children.
因此，二叉树仅意味着每个节点都有两个孩子。
There's a bit more structure in this guy.
这个家伙有更多的结构。
So if I look at the root, if I look at 23,
所以，如果我看根，如果我看23，
all the nodes to the left are smaller.
左侧的所有节点都较小。
All the nodes to the right are bigger.
右边的所有节点都更大。
Now, if I look at 8, all the nodes to the left are smaller,
现在，如果我看8，左侧的所有节点都较小，
all the nodes to the right are greater.
右边的所有节点都更大。
This additional rep invariant defines a binary search tree.
这个附加的rep不变式定义了一个二进制搜索树。
This is what we talked about in class.
这就是我们在课堂上谈到的。
BST.
BST。
Why would I want to have this rep invariant?
为什么我要让这个代表不变？
It sounds like a pain to maintain nodes
维护节点听起来很痛苦
with all these ordering constraints.
所有这些排序约束。
What's the advantage of doing that?
这样做的好处是什么？
AUDIENCE: Search is fast.
听众：搜索很快。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Search is fast.
搜索速度很快。
How do I do search?
我该如何搜寻？
If you're looking for 42 or for 16,
如果您要寻找42或16，
you'd be like, oh, it's less than 23.
你会想，哦，不到23岁。
I'll get on this path.
我走这条路。
PROFESSOR: So start at the root, compare my key to the root.
教授：因此，从根开始，将我的密钥与根进行比较。
If it's smaller, go left.
如果较小，请向左走。
If it's bigger, go right.
如果更大，请继续。
Then keep doing that until I arrive somewhere
然后继续做，直到我到达某个地方
or until I arrive at a dead end if I'm looking for 14.
或直到我走到尽头时才寻找14。
This is a lot like binary search.
这很像二进制搜索。
Binary search in an array, you look at the middle.
在数组中进行二进制搜索，您可以看中间。
If your key is smaller, go left.
如果密钥较小，请向左移动。
If your key is bigger, then go right.
如果您的钥匙更大，请继续。
Let's look at the code for a little bit.
让我们看一下代码。
Look at the BST Node Class, and you'll
看一下BST节点类，您将
see that it has the fields that we have up here.
看到它具有我们在此处拥有的字段。
And look at the Find method, and this is pretty much
看一下Find方法，这差不多
the binary search code.
二进制搜索代码。
Lines 8 and 9 have the return condition when you're happy
第8行和第9行在您满意时具有返回条件
and you found the key, and then line 10 compares
然后您找到了密钥，然后第10行进行了比较
the key that you're looking for with the key in the node
您要查找的密钥与节点中的密钥
that you're at, and then lines 11, 14, 16, and 19 are pretty
您所在的位置，然后第11、14、16和19行就很漂亮
much copy pasted, except one of them
除了其中之一外，粘贴了很多副本
deals with the left case, the other one
处理左边的情况，另一个
deals with the right case.
处理正确的案例。
What is the running time for Find?
查找的运行时间是几点？
AUDIENCE: Wouldn't it be log N, right?
听众：是不是log N，对吗？
PROFESSOR: I wish.
教授：我希望。
If this is all you have to do to get log N,
如果这是获取日志N所需要做的一切，
then I would have to write a lot less code.
那么我将不得不编写更少的代码。
So not quite log N. We will have to go through next lecture
因此，没有完全登录N。我们将不得不进行下一讲
to get to log N. Until then, what's the running time?
才能登录N。在那之前，运行时间是多少？
AUDIENCE: Order h.
听众：订单h。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So you told me at the beginning it's unbalanced.
所以您在一开始就告诉我这是不平衡的。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: So then it's not going to be fast.
教授：所以那不会很快。
OK, so order h.
好，所以订购h。
The reason why we care about h, and the reason
我们关心h的原因以及原因
we don't say order N, is because next
我们不说订单N，是因为下一个
lecture after we learn how to balance a tree,
在学习如何平衡一棵树之后的讲座
there's some magic that you can do to these binary search trees
您可以对这些二进制搜索树执行一些操作
to guarantee that the height is order of log N.
以确保高度为对数N的量级。
And then we'll go through all the running times that we have
然后我们将经历所有的运行时间
and replace h with log N.
并将h替换为logN。
Now, it happens that in this case, if you would have told
现在，在这种情况下，如果您会告诉
me order N, I couldn't argue with you because worst case,
我下令N，我无法与您争论，因为最坏的情况是，
searches are order N. Can someone give me a binary search
搜索是顺序N。有人可以给我二进制搜索吗
tree that exposes this degenerate case?
暴露这种退化情况的树？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: If it's completely unbalanced
听众：如果完全不平衡
and every node is greater than the parent nodes.
并且每个节点都大于父节点。
PROFESSOR: So give me some inserts that create it.
教授：所以请给我一些创建它的插件。
AUDIENCE: Insert 5.
听众：插入5。
PROFESSOR: 5.
教授：5。
AUDIENCE: Insert 10.
听众：插入10。
PROFESSOR: 10.
教授：10。
AUDIENCE: Insert 15.
听众：插入15。
PROFESSOR: 15.
教授：15。
AUDIENCE: Insert 20.
听众：插入20。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
And I could keep going.
而且我可以继续。
I could say, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
我可以说1、2、3、4、5。
I could say 5, 10, 15.
我可以说5、10、15
As long as these keep growing, this is basically
只要这些保持增长，这基本上是
going to be a list, so searching is
将成为一个列表，所以搜索是
order N. This is a degenerate case.
N阶。这是一个简并的情况。
Turns out it doesn't happen too often in practice.
事实证明，这种情况在实践中并不经常发生。
If you have random data, the height will be roughly log N.
如果您有随机数据，则高度大约为logN。
But in order to avoid those degenerate cases,
但是为了避免这些退化的情况，
we'll be doing balanced trees later on.
稍后我们将做平衡树。
So we covered Find.
因此，我们介绍了Find。
We know it's order h.
我们知道这是命令h。
How do you insert, really quickly?
如何快速插入？
AUDIENCE: Do you mean in searching
听众：您的意思是搜索
when it's balanced or unbalanced?
什么时候平衡或不平衡？
PROFESSOR: This guy.
教授：这个家伙。
So the trees look exactly the same.
所以树木看起来完全一样。
If it's balanced, it's going to look more
如果平衡，它将看起来更多
like that than like this.
像这样比那样。
Actually, this is balanced.
实际上，这是平衡的。
This is perfectly unbalanced.
这是完全不平衡的。
This is somewhere in the middle.
这是在中间的某个地方。
If it's balanced, it's just going to look more like this,
如果平衡的话，看起来会更像这样，
but it's still a binary search tree.
但它仍然是二叉搜索树。
How would you insert a node?
您将如何插入节点？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: Can't you start at the root
听众：你不能从根本开始
and find your way down, and then the first open child
然后找到路，然后是第一个开放的孩子
that you see that's applicable to your element, state it then?
您看到适用于您的元素的状态，然后声明？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So if I wanted to insert 14, which way do I go?
因此，如果我想插入14，我应该走哪条路？
AUDIENCE: So you'd look at 23, and you'd say,
听众：所以你看23，你会说，
it's less than 23, go left.
不到23，向左走。
You'd look at 8.
您会看到8。
You'd say, it's greater than 8.
您会说，它大于8。
You'd go right.
你会走对的。
Look at 16.
看16。
You'd say it's less, so you go left.
你会说它少了，所以你走了。
15, it's less.
15，更少。
Then you have an open spot so you stick it there.
然后，您有一个开放的位置，可以将其粘贴在那里。
PROFESSOR: Excellent.
教授：非常好。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: I have a question.
听众：我有一个问题。
What if we want to insert 5?
如果要插入5怎么办？
Then--
然后 -
PROFESSOR: So if you want to insert who?
教授：那么，如果您想插入谁？
AUDIENCE: 5.
听众：5。
Or actually no, we can't.
或实际上不，我们不能。
I'm thinking, is there any case in which need to move a node?
我在想，是否有需要移动节点的情况？
PROFESSOR: How would you insert 5?
教授：您将如何插入5？
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
What would you do for 5?
你要做什么5？
AUDIENCE: For 5, then we'd insert it to the right of 4,
听众：对于5，然后将其插入4的右侧
right?
对？
PROFESSOR: Smaller, smaller, greater, 5.
教授：更小，更小，更大，5。
Right?
对？
AUDIENCE: So there would be no case in which we'd
听众：因此，在任何情况下我们都不会
need to swap nodes or something?
需要交换节点或其他东西吗？
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
You're thinking ahead.
你在想
We'll talk about that a little later when we get to deleting.
我们稍后再讨论删除内容。
As long as you follow a path in the tree, the path that finding
只要您遵循树中的路径，
would get you to, as soon as you hit a dead end,
会让您一踏入死胡同，
that's where your node belongs.
这就是您的节点所属的位置。
Because you know next time you're going to search for it,
因为您知道下次要搜索它，
the search is going to follow that path and find the node.
搜索将遵循该路径并找到节点。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: If you have values are the same, like two
听众：如果您的值相同，例如两个
nodes at the same number, does it
节点数目相同
matter which side you put it on?
不管戴哪一边？
PROFESSOR: You don't.
教授：你不知道。
AUDIENCE: Oh, I see.
听众：哦，我知道了。
It's more like you would only have four 1's in the tree.
这更像是树中只有四个1。
PROFESSOR: Yes.
教授：是的。
So if you're trying to store keys and values,
因此，如果您要存储键和值，
then what you'd have to do if you
那你该怎么办
want to allow multiple values for the same key
想要为同一个键允许多个值
is you have a linked list going off
你有一个链表关闭吗
of this, which node becomes an array of values
其中，哪个节点成为值数组
aside from the key.
除了钥匙。
Smart question.
聪明的问题。
Thank you.
谢谢。
That trips you up every time you do actual code,
每次您执行实际代码时，都会使您烦恼，
so that's the right question to ask yourself
所以这是问自己的正确问题
when you're implementing this.
当您执行此操作时。
Will I have duplicates?
我会重复吗？
How do I handle them?
我该如何处理？
We don't.
我们没有。
We take the easy way out.
我们采取简单的方法。
So if you look at Insert, on the next page,
因此，如果您在下一页上查看“插入”，
you will see that the code is pretty much the Find code
您将看到该代码几乎是“查找”代码
copy pasted, except when Self Left is None
复制粘贴，除非“自我左”为“无”时
or Self Right is None, instead of returning,
或“自我权利”为“无”，而不是返回，
it creates a new node.
它创建一个新节点。
Does that make sense to people?
这对人们有意义吗？
All right.
好吧。
So Delete is going to be the hardest operation for today.
因此，删除将是当今最困难的操作。
Before we do that, let's do a warm up operation.
在此之前，让我们进行预热操作。
Let's say I want to implement Find Next Larger, also called
假设我要实现“查找下一个更大的对象”，也称为
Successor in some implementations.
在某些实现中的后继。
So I have a node.
所以我有一个节点。
Say I have node 8, and I want to find the next key
假设我有节点8，我想找到下一个密钥
in the tree that's strictly larger than 8
在严格大于8的树中
but smaller than anything else.
但比其他任何东西都小。
So if I would take these nodes and write them down in order,
因此，如果我将这些节点取下来并按顺序写下来，
I want to find the element that would go right after it.
我想找到紧随其后的元素。
How do I do that?
我怎么做？
Don't cheat.
不要作弊
Don't look at the code, or make my life easier and do searches.
不要看代码，也不要让我的生活更轻松并进行搜索。
AUDIENCE: Go down one to the right,
听众：向右下移一个，
and you try to get down left as far as you can.
然后您尽力往左走。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Very good.
很好。
So I have a node, and it has some subtree here,
所以我有一个节点，这里有一些子树，
so I can go to the right here, I can go all the way left.
所以我可以在这里向右走，我可以一直向左走。
We have an operation that does this,
我们有一个操作可以做到这一点，
and it's called Min for a tree.
它被称为Min for a tree。
In order to find the minimum in a binary search tree,
为了在二叉搜索树中找到最小值，
you keep going left.
你一直往左走。
For example, in this case, you get 4, which is good.
例如，在这种情况下，您得到4，这很好。
So the way you would code this up is if you have Min,
因此，如果有Min，则可以编写此代码
you go to the right if you can, and then
如果可以的话，您会向右走，然后
you call Min on the subtree.
您在子树上调用Min。
And you can see that lines 3 and 4 do exactly that.
您会看到第3行和第4行正是这样做的。
Good guess.
不错的猜测。
But you can line 1 says case one,
但您可以在第1行说第一种情况，
so you have the right answer for one case.
因此，对于一种情况，您有正确的答案。
Now we have to handle more difficult cases.
现在我们必须处理更困难的情况。
What if instead, I go down a bunch of nodes,
相反，如果我走了一大堆节点，
and I want to find the successor for this guy, for example,
例如，我想找到这个人的继任者，
and there's nothing here.
这里什么都没有。
What do I do?
我该怎么办？
So if I want to find the successor for 8, what do I do?
因此，如果我想找到8的后继者，我该怎么办？
Sorry.
抱歉。
It has an answer.
它有一个答案。
What if I want to find the successor for 4?
如果我想找到4的后继者怎么办？
AUDIENCE: Go up one.
听众：上去一个。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Go up one.
上去一个。
Why does that work?
为什么行得通？
AUDIENCE: You know it's going to be greater.
听众：您知道会越来越大。
PROFESSOR: So I'm going up right.
教授：所以我要走了。
So I know that everything here is guaranteed to be smaller,
所以我知道这里的所有东西都一定会变小，
everything here is guaranteed to be greater than this guy.
保证这里的一切都比这个家伙还伟大。
This guy is up right, so this is guaranteed to be greater
这个家伙是对的，所以可以保证更大
than this, and everything here is
比这更重要的是
guaranteed to be greater than this, and so on and so forth
保证大于此值，依此类推等等
for the entire tree.
为整棵树。
So if I go up right, I'm happy.
因此，如果我正确向上走，我会很高兴。
I definitely found my answer.
我绝对找到了答案。
Now, what if I have something that looks like this,
现在，如果我有类似这样的东西，
and I want to find the successor for this guy?
我想找这个人的继任者？
AUDIENCE: There is none.
听众：没有。
PROFESSOR: In this case, there is none
教授：在这种情况下，没有
if there's nothing else here.
如果这里没有别的。
What if I have this, but then I have this?
如果我有这个但我有这个怎么办？
So I came down this way.
所以我就这样走了。
AUDIENCE: Are you saying you're calling on that last node?
听众：您是说您正在呼叫最后一个节点吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: Find the larger?
听众：寻找更大的？
I guess you'd just trace back up.
我想你只是追溯。
PROFESSOR: And where do I stop?
教授：那我应该在哪里停下来？
AUDIENCE: It affects the tree, so you go up one from there.
听众：它会影响树，因此您从那里上一棵树。
You don't stop there.
你不止于此。
PROFESSOR: Why can't I stop here?
教授：为什么我不能在这里停下来？
AUDIENCE: Because you know that that-- not necessarily.
听众：因为你知道那-不一定。
AUDIENCE: You know that everything in that long branch
听众：你知道那个长分支中的一切
right there is less than that node [INAUDIBLE].
就比那个节点少[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: This is to the left of this guy,
教授：这是这个人的左边，
so this guy has to be greater than everything here,
所以这个家伙必须比这里的一切都要强大，
and then you can repeat the argument that we had before.
然后您可以重复我们以前的论点。
So here, we could stop right away
所以在这里，我们可以马上停下来
because we could branch left.
因为我们可以向左分支。
In this case, you have to go up until you're
在这种情况下，您必须上升直到
able to go left and up.
能够向上和向左走。
If you get to the root, then what happened?
如果您扎根，那么发生了什么？
Then we're in this case, and you have no successor.
那么在这种情况下，您就没有继任者了。
So take a look at the code.
因此，请看一下代码。
The next larger, lines 1 through 9.
下一个较大的行1至9。
Case two, 6 through 8, does exactly that.
案例2到6到8正是这样做的。
If I can't go to my right and find the tree there,
如果我不能在右边找到那棵树，
then I go up through my parent chain,
然后我浏览我的父母链，
and as long as I have to go up to the left,
只要我必须向左走
so as long as I'm the right child of my parent,
只要我是我父母的合适孩子，
I have to keep going.
我必须继续前进。
The moment I find the parent where I'm the left child,
当我找到父母在我的左生子的那一刻，
I stop.
我停下。
That's my successor.
那是我的继任者。
What if I would have to find the predecessor instead?
如果我不得不找到前任怎么办？
So the element that's smaller than me
所以这个元素比我小
but bigger than everything else in the tree.
但比树上的所有其他东西都大。
What would I do?
我该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: It's just the opposite.
听众：相反。
PROFESSOR: Just the opposite.
教授：相反。
So how do I do the opposite?
那我该怎么做相反呢？
AUDIENCE: You can take the max of the left side tree,
听众：您可以最大程度地利用左侧树，
or traverse up, and if that's less than--
或向上移动，如果小于-
PROFESSOR: OK, so if I have a left subtree, fine.
教授：好的，如果我有一个左子树，那就好。
Call max on it and get the rightmost node there.
在其上调用max，并在那里找到最右边的节点。
If not, I go up, and when do I stop?
如果没有，我会上去，什么时候停下来？
When I go left or right?
当我左走还是右走？
AUDIENCE: You'd have to go right.
听众：你必须走对。
Is that right?
那正确吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So last time, in this case, when I was going up,
所以上一次，在这种情况下，当我上升时，
if I was going left, I had to keep going,
如果我要离开，我必须继续前进，
and the moment I went right, I was happy and I stopped.
当我走对的那一刻，我很高兴，我停了下来。
What if I want to find the predecessor?
如果我想找到前任怎么办？
It's the opposite, right?
相反，对吗？
So I will go this way, and the moment I can go this way,
所以我会走这条路，当我能走这条路的那一刻，
I'm done.
我受够了。
How do you do this in code?
您如何用代码做到这一点？
Slightly tricky.
有点棘手。
Just slightly, I promise.
我保证，只是一点点。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: It's hard.
教授：很难。
What I would do is copy paste the code,
我要做的就是复制粘贴代码，
replace "left" with "right" everywhere, and replace "min"
到处将“ left”替换为“ right”，并替换“ min”
with "max."
与“最大”。
You get it done.
您完成了。
So we talked about how the tree is symmetric, right?
所以我们讨论了树是如何对称的，对吗？
So every time, instead of saying "left," you say "right,"
因此，每次都说“对”而不是说“左”
and instead of saying "min," you say "max."
而不是说“最小”，而是说“最大”。
That's how you do this.
这就是您的做法。
How do we do deletions?
我们如何删除？
So suppose I'm in this tree and I want to delete 15.
因此，假设我在这棵树中，我想删除15。
What do I do?
我该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: Kill it.
听众：杀了它。
PROFESSOR: Kill it.
教授：杀了它。
Very good.
很好。
What if I want to delete 16?
如果要删除16怎么办？
What do I do?
我该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: You need to put 15 where 16 is.
听众：您需要将15放在16。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So I would put 15 here.
所以我要在这里放15。
So I had 16.
所以我有16岁
Suppose I have a big tree here.
假设我这里有一棵大树。
Actually, let's go for an easier case.
实际上，让我们来看一个简单的案例。
Let's say I have this tree here.
假设我在这里有这棵树。
So you're here, you have a big tree here,
所以你在这里，你有一棵大树，
you don't have anything here, and you
你这里什么都没有，你
want to delete this guy.
要删除此人。
AUDIENCE: You know that everything less
听众：你知道一切都更少
than the top node is going to be less than it,
比顶部节点要小于它，
so you can just move that up.
因此您可以将其向上移动。
PROFESSOR: Everything less than this guy is also
教授：比这家伙还少的一切
going to be less than this guy.
会比这个家伙少。
So you're saying move the whole tree up.
所以您说的是将整个树向上移动。
AUDIENCE: Yep.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: So the way we do that is
教授：所以我们这样做的方法是
we'd take this node's left link and make it point here,
我们将使用该节点的左链接并将其指向此处，
and take this guy's parent link and make it point here,
并把这个人的父母链接指向此处，
and this guy sort of goes away.
这个家伙就走了
So we have two cases for deleting.
因此，我们有两种情况需要删除。
We have if you're a leaf, we'll take you out.
如果您是一片叶子，我们会带您出去的。
Sorry.
抱歉。
I got confused.
我很困惑。
If you have one child and that child
如果你有一个孩子，那个孩子
is in the same direction as your parent, then you can do this.
与您父母的方向相同，那么您可以执行此操作。
What if you have one child, but it's a zigzag like this?
如果您有一个孩子，但是像这样的锯齿状怎么办？
What do you do?
你是做什么？
AUDIENCE: It's still greater than, so you do the same thing.
听众：仍然大于，所以您做同样的事情。
PROFESSOR: Exactly.
教授：是的。
Same thing.
一样。
Just change this guy, change this guy, and I'm happy.
只是换这个人，换这个人，我很高兴。
So it doesn't matter if you have a zigzag or a straight line.
因此，无论您是锯齿形还是直线形都没关系。
It might help you think about it to convince yourself
它可以帮助您考虑一下以说服自己
that the code is correct, but in the end, you do the same thing.
该代码是正确的，但最后，您做同样的事情。
Now, what if I want to delete node 8?
现在，如果要删除节点8，该怎么办？
So what if I have a nasty case where I want to delete this guy
那如果我有一个讨厌的案例要删除这个家伙怎么办
and it has children both on the left and on the right?
它的左边和右边都有孩子？
AUDIENCE: You have to take 8, compare it to its parent
听众：您必须输入8，并将其与其父级进行比较
and compare it to its right child,
并将其与合适的孩子进行比较
and see which one is greater in order
看看哪个更大
to figure out which node gets replaced in its spot.
找出哪个节点在其位置被替换。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So there is replacing that's going to happen.
因此，将要进行替换。
The answer is really tricky.
答案确实很棘手。
I always forget this when coding.
我总是在编码时忘记这一点。
Try to understand it, and if it doesn't work,
尝试了解它，如果它不起作用，
refer to the textbook.
请参阅教科书。
When you forget it, because you will, refer to the textbook
当您忘记它时，可以参考该教科书
or to the internet.
或上网。
So what you do is I can't just magically replace this node
所以你要做的就是我不能神奇地替换这个节点
with one of the subtrees, but we talked right
与其中一个子树，但我们说的没错
before this about Next Greater, so finding a node's successor.
在此之前，关于Next Greater，请先找到节点的后继者。
If this node has both a left subtree and a right subtree,
如果此节点同时具有左子树和右子树，
then I know that if I call Find Successor on it,
那我知道如果我打电话给它，
I'm going to go somewhere inside here,
我要去这里里面的某个地方
and I'm going to find a node somewhere in here all the way
我将一直在这里找到一个节点
to the left that is this guy's successor.
在左边是这个家伙的继任者。
So what I'm going to do is I'm going
所以我要做的是
to delete this node instead, and then I'm going to take its key
删除该节点，然后我要获取其密钥
and put it up here.
放在这里
So if I want to delete 8, what I do is I find its successor,
因此，如果要删除8，我要做的就是找到它的后继者，
then I delete it, then I take the 15 that was here-- you
然后我删除它，然后取那15个-你
can see it, right?
可以看到吧？
It's still there.
它仍然在那里。
Put it here.
放在这里。
So the reason this works is that everything here
所以这样做的原因是这里的一切
is greater than this guy.
比这个家伙还伟大。
Everything here is smaller than this guy.
这里的一切都比这个家伙小。
This is the next node that's greater than this guy,
这是下一个比这个家伙更大的节点，
but everything else is bigger than it,
但其他一切都比它更大，
right, because we wanted it to be a successor.
是的，因为我们希望它成为继任者。
So if I take this value and I put it up here,
因此，如果我采用此值并将其放在这里，
everything in here is still going to be greater than it.
这里的一切仍将大于它。
This is a successor of this guy, so everything here
这是这个家伙的继任者，所以这里的一切
is still going to be smaller than the successor.
仍将小于后继者。
Great.
大。
In order to do a delete, I find the successor,
为了进行删除，我找到了后继者，
and then I call Delete on it.
然后我叫删除。
How do I know that this will end?
我怎么知道这将结束？
How do I know that I'm not going to go
我怎么知道我不会去
into a loop that runs forever?
进入永远运行的循环？
AUDIENCE: Because it's not--
听众：因为不是-
AUDIENCE: It's acyclic, right?
听众：它是非循环的，对吗？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
First answer, good.
第一个答案，很好。
Eventually, worst case, I'm going to get to the maximum,
最终，在最坏的情况下，我将发挥最大作用，
and then not going on have to delete the successor anymore.
然后就不必再删除后继了。
Now, another thing to note here is
现在，这里要注意的另一件事是
that if this guy is the successor of this guy,
如果这个人是这个人的继任者，
it can't have anything on the left, because if it would,
它的左边不能有任何东西，因为如果有的话，
then whatever is down here has to be bigger than this,
那么这里的任何东西都必须大于这个，
and whatever's to the left of this node
以及该节点左侧的任何内容
has to be smaller than this.
必须小于这个。
But we said that this is the successor of this,
但是我们说这是继任者，
so there's nothing here.
所以这里什么都没有。
So this will be one of the easy cases that we talked about.
因此，这将是我们讨论过的简单案例之一。
The successor either has no kids,
继任者没有孩子
or it has only one child, only one subtree.
或者它只有一个孩子，只有一棵子树。
So then I can delete it using one of the easy cases.
因此，我可以使用一种简单的情况将其删除。
So in fact, worst case that happens in a delete is my node
所以事实上，在删除中发生的最坏情况是我的节点
has two subtrees.
有两个子树。
Then I find the successor that's only going to have one subtree,
然后，我发现只有一个子树的后继者，
I change my links there, and I'm done.
我在那里更改了链接，然后完成。
What is the running time for Delete?
Delete的运行时间是几点？
AUDIENCE: Is it order h, because you should do it
听众：是命令h，因为你应该这样做
all the way down to the bottom of the tree, right?
一直到树的底部，对不对？
PROFESSOR: You have the right answer.
教授：您的回答正确。
Let's see why it's order h.
让我们看看为什么要订购h。
It has to be order h, right?
必须是命令h，对不对？
Otherwise, the tree would be too slow.
否则，树将太慢。
If it's order N, then it's bad.
如果是N阶，那就不好了。
So why would Delete be order h?
那么为什么删除命令是h？
This was a heap, right, so I can't use this.
这是一堆，对，所以我不能使用它。
I'm going to write "delete" here again.
我将在这里再次写“删除”。
So the first thing you do is you have to search for the key,
因此，您要做的第一件事就是必须搜索密钥，
right?
对？
That's order h.
那是命令h。
Now, if it's a happy case, if it's case one or two,
现在，如果是一个快乐的情况，如果是一两个情况，
you change some links and you're done.
您更改一些链接就可以了。
What's the time for that?
现在几点了？
AUDIENCE: Constant.
听众：不变。
PROFESSOR: Constant.
教授：不变。
So happy case, order h for sure.
非常高兴，请确定要订购h。
Now sad case.
现在可悲的情况。
If you have two children, what do you
如果您有两个孩子，那您呢
have to do after you realize that you have two subtrees?
您意识到自己有两个子树后必须做什么？
AUDIENCE: Find the successor.
听众：找到继任者。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
What's the running time for finding a successor?
寻找继任者的时间是多少？
AUDIENCE: Order h.
听众：订单h。
PROFESSOR: Order h.
教授：命令h。
Once I find the successor, what do I do?
找到继任者后，我该怎么办？
Call Delete on that, and what happens?
致电Delete，会发生什么？
It's a happy case or a sad case?
这是一个快乐的案例还是一个悲伤的案例？
AUDIENCE: It's a happy case.
听众：这是一个快乐的案例。
PROFESSOR: Happy case, a few links get swapped,
教授：很高兴，一些链接被交换了，
constant time.
恒定的时间。
So worst case, order h plus order h.
因此，最坏的情况是命令h加命令h。
Order h.
订单h。
So insertions are order h, deletions are order h.
因此，插入是顺序h，删除是顺序h。
AUDIENCE: The first one.
听众：第一个。
Because the second one is from finding the successor.
因为第二个是从寻找继任者。
What is the first one for?
第一个是做什么用的？
PROFESSOR: Finding the node for a key in the tree.
教授：在树中找到键的节点。
So if I say Delete 8, then you have to find 8.
因此，如果我说删除8，那么您必须找到8。
If I give you the node, then you don't have that.
如果我给您节点，那么您就没有了。
Good question.
好问题。
It's a good question.
这是一个好问题。
Thank you.
谢谢。
So that's insertion.
这就是插入。
That's deletion.
那是删除。
Let's look at the code for Delete.
让我们看一下删除的代码。
Looks kind of long.
看起来有点长。
So lines through 21, happy case or sad case?
那么，通过21行，快乐案例还是悲伤案例？
Try to do it by looking at the "if"
尝试通过查看“如果”来做到这一点
instead of looking at the comments.
而不是看评论。
So lines through 21 for Delete.
因此，通过21行删除。
AUDIENCE: On this tree?
听众：在这棵树上？
Which tree, because there are two deletes?
哪棵树，因为有两个删除？
PROFESSOR: Oh really?
教授：真的吗？
Sorry.
抱歉。
Why do we have two deletes?
为什么我们有两个删除？
AUDIENCE: There's BST Delete and then there's BST Node Delete.
听众：有BST删除，然后有BST节点删除。
PROFESSOR: So BST Delete.
教授：请删除BST。
Finds the node, and then calls Delete on the node.
查找节点，然后在该节点上调用Delete。
And then if the node is a tree's root,
然后，如果节点是树的根，
then it updates the tree's root.
然后更新树的根。
So let's look at the nodes delete.
因此，让我们看一下节点删除。
Oh, I see.
哦，我明白了。
I think I was looking at the wrong one.
我想我看错了。
Thank you.
谢谢。
My Delete was much longer than yours.
我的删除比您的删除时间长得多。
So lines 3 through 12, happy case or sad case?
那么第3行到第12行是快乐的情况还是悲伤的情况？
Look at the "if" on line 3 and tell me,
看一下第3行的“如果”，然后告诉我，
what case is it going for?
这是什么情况？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: If it doesn't have a left child
教授：如果没有孩子
or it doesn't have a right child,
或没有合适的孩子
is that the happy case or the sad case?
是快乐的情况还是悲伤的情况？
AUDIENCE: Happy.
听众：很高兴。
PROFESSOR: Happy case.
教授：很高兴。
So lines 4 through 12 handle the happy case.
因此，第4至12行处理了这种情况。
Lines 14 through 16 handle the sad case.
第14行到第16行处理这种情况。
Do lines 14 through 16 make sense?
第14到16行有意义吗？
Find the successor, then swap the keys,
找到继任者，然后交换密钥，
then delete that successor.
然后删除该后继者。
Now, lines 4 through 11 are pretty much what
现在，第4至11行几乎是什么
we talked about here, except I can't draw arrows on the board
我们在这里讨论过，除了我不能在板上画箭头
and instead I have to change left and right links.
相反，我必须更改左右链接。
Line 4 has to see if we're a left child or a right child,
第4行必须查看我们是左孩子还是右孩子，
and then lines 5 through 7 and 9 through 11 are pretty much
然后第5至7行和9至11行
copy paste, swap left with right.
复制粘贴，左右互换。
And they changed the links like we changed them here.
他们更改了链接，就像我们在此处更改链接一样。
Do we have any questions on Deletes?
我们对删除有任何疑问吗？
AUDIENCE: So if the successor had a right child,
听众：所以，如果继任者有一个合适的孩子，
then all you do, you just do the workaround thing where
然后您所做的所有事情，您只需执行解决方法
you just--
你刚才 -
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So the case that it doesn't have two children.
因此，它没有两个孩子。
As long as it doesn't have both children,
只要没有两个孩子
you're in the happy case and you can do some link swapping.
您情况很好，可以进行一些链接交换。
Are you guys burned out already?
你们已经精疲力尽了吗？
Fair enough.
很公平。
I left a part out.
我遗漏了一部分。
What I left out is how to augment a binary tree.
我遗漏的是如何增加二叉树。
So binary trees by default can answer the question,
因此默认情况下，二叉树可以回答这个问题，
what's the minimum node in a tree in order h.
树中按h顺序排列的最小节点是多少？
You go all the way to the left, you find the minimum.
您一直走到最左边，找到最小值。
That's the minimum.
那是最低的。
It turns out that if you make a node a little bit fatter,
事实证明，如果使节点更胖，
so if instead of storing, say, 23 in this node, I store 23,
因此，如果我不是在该节点中存储23，而是存储23，
and I store the fact that the minimum in my left subtree
我将最小值存储在我的左子树中
is 4, then it turns out that I can answer the question
是4，那么事实证明我可以回答这个问题
in constant time, what's the minimum?
在恒定时间内，最低要求是多少？
Oh gee, if you store the minimum here,
哦，天哪，如果您将最小值存储在这里，
of course you can retrieve it in constant time, right?
当然，您可以在固定时间内检索它，对吗？
The hard part is, how do you handle insertions and updates
困难的部分是，您如何处理插入和更新
in the same time?
在同一时间？
So the idea is that if I have a node
所以想法是，如果我有一个节点
and I have a function here, say the minimum of everything,
我在这里有一个功能，要说的是最少的，
if I have two children, here they're 15 and 42,
如果我有两个孩子，他们分别是15岁和42岁
and say the minimum in this tree is 4
并说这棵树的最小值是4
and the minimum in this tree is.
这棵树的最小值是
So if I already computed the function for these guys,
因此，如果我已经为这些人计算了函数，
how do I compute the function for this?
我该如何计算函数？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] and compare it?
听众：[听不清]，然后进行比较吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Take the minimum of these two guys, right?
拿这两个家伙中最小的一个吧？
There are some special cases if you don't have a child.
如果您没有孩子，则有一些特殊情况。
If you don't have a left child, then you're the minimum.
如果您没有孩子，那么您就是最低要求。
But you write down those special cases,
但是你写下那些特殊情况
and you can compute this in how much time?
您可以计算多少时间？
AUDIENCE: Order h, right?
听众：命令h，对不对？
PROFESSOR: What if I already computed the answer
教授：如果我已经计算出答案，该怎么办
for the children?
为了孩子？
How much time does it take to compute
计算需要多少时间
the answer for a single node?
一个节点的答案？
AUDIENCE: Constant.
听众：不变。
PROFESSOR: Constant.
教授：不变。
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: For a tree, though.
听众：不过是一棵树。
PROFESSOR: For a tree, it's order h.
教授：对于一棵树，它的顺序是h。
Yeah.
是的
You're getting ahead.
您正在前进。
You're rushing me.
你在催我。
You're not letting me finish.
你不让我说完。
AUDIENCE: Are you saying that we store the minimum value?
听众：您是说我们存储最小值吗？
PROFESSOR: So for every--
教授：所以对于每个人-
AUDIENCE: Each node has a field that
听众：每个节点都有一个字段，
says what the minimum value is in that tree.
说出那棵树的最小值。
PROFESSOR: Yep, exactly.
教授：好的。
So for each node, what's the minimum in the subtree.
因此，对于每个节点，子树中的最小值是多少。
So if I add a node here, suppose I add three
所以如果我在这里添加一个节点，假设我添加了三个
and I had my minimums, what changed?
我有最低要求，什么改变了？
This subtree changed, this subtree changed,
这个子树变了，这个子树变了，
this subtree changed, and then this subtree changed.
此子树更改，然后此子树更改。
So I have to update the minimums here, here, here, here.
所以我必须在这里，这里，这里，这里更新最小值。
Nothing else changed.
没有其他改变。
Outside the path where I did the Insert,
在我执行插入操作的路径之外，
nothing changed, so I don't have to update anything.
没什么改变，所以我不必更新任何东西。
So what I do is after the Insert, I go back up
所以我要做的是在插入之后，我回去
and I re-compute the values.
然后我重新计算值。
So here, I'll have 3.
所以在这里，我有3。
I go back up 3, 3, 3.
我备份3、3、3。
AUDIENCE: You could when you're passing down, though.
听众：不过，当你传下去时，你可以。
When you're going down that column,
当您浏览该专栏时，
you can just compare it on the way down.
您可以在下降的过程中进行比较。
You don't have to go back up, right?
您不必备份，对吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So the advantage of doing it the way I'm saying it
所以以我所说的方式做的好处
is that you can have other functions instead of minimum.
是您可以具有其他功能，而不是最少的功能。
As long as you can compute the function
只要你能算出函数
inside the parent in constant time
在恒定时间内进入父母
using the function from the children,
利用孩子们的功能
it makes sense to compute the function on the children first.
首先计算子代函数是有意义的。
There's an obvious function that I can't tell you
有一个明显的功能我不能告诉你
because that's on the Pset, but when you see the next Pset,
因为它在Pset上，但是当您看到下一个Pset时，
you'll see what I mean.
你会明白我的意思的。
So if you have a function where you
所以如果你有一个功能
know the result for the children and you can compute the result
知道孩子的结果，您可以计算结果
for the parent in constant time, then after you do the Insert,
固定时间为父级，然后在执行插入操作后，
you go up on the path and you re-compute the function.
您沿着路径前进，然后重新计算该函数。
When you delete, what do you do?
删除后，您会做什么？
AUDIENCE: Same thing.
听众：一样。
PROFESSOR: Same thing.
教授：也是。
If this goes away, then this subtree changed, and then
如果此方法消失，则此子树将更改，然后
if there would be something else here,
如果这里还有其他事情，
then this subtree changed, but nothing else changed.
然后这个子树改变了，但是没有其他改变。
So whenever you do an Insert or a Delete, all you have to do
因此，无论何时执行插入或删除操作，都要做
is go back up the path to the parent
是回到父级的路径
and re-compute the function that you're trying to compute.
并重新计算您要计算的函数。
And that's tree augmentation.
那就是树的增强。
Does this make sense somewhat?
这有道理吗？
That's it.
而已。
So what you'll find in lecture notes
所以您会在讲义中找到
is a harder way of doing it that works for minimum,
是一种很难做到的方法，但效果最低
but what I told you works for everything.
但是我告诉你的一切都是可行的。
So don't tell people I told you how to do this for everything.
所以，不要告诉别人我告诉过你如何做到这一点。
Sure nobody's going to know.
当然没有人会知道。